Here kitty, kitty, kitty...
Josie and the Pussycats is a comedy, music film directed by Deborah Kaplan.
Josie, Melody and Val are three small-town girl musicians determined to take their rock band out of
their garage and straight to the top, while remaining true to their look, style and sound.
They get a record deal which brings fame and fortune but soon realize they are
pawns of two people who want to control the youth of America.
They must clear their names, even if it means losing fame and fortune.
Josie McCoy, played by Rachael Leigh Cook.
Valerie Brown, played by Rosario Dawson.
Melody Valentine, played by Tara Reid.
Wyatt Frame, played by Alan Cumming.
Fiona, played by Parker Posey.
Alan M., played by Gabriel Mann.
Josie and the Pussycats is a 2001 musical comedy film co-produced by
Universal Pictures and Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Pictures.
Written and directed by Harry Elfont and Deborah Kaplan, the film is based on both the
Archie Comics series and the Hanna-Barbera cartoon of the same name.
Filmed entirely in Vancouver, Canada, the film features Rachael Leigh Cook, Tara Reid, and Rosario Dawson as the
Pussycats, with Alan Cumming, Parker Posey, Gabriel Mann, Paulo Costanzo, and Missi Pyle in supporting roles.
It was released in the United States on April 11, 2001 by Universal Pictures with the
international distribution held by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (through 20th Century Fox).
The film's soundtrack album was well received, charting at No.
16 on the Billboard 200 and quickly achieving Gold status.
The film was a critical and commercial disappointment upon its initial release, grossing $14.9
million against a $22–39 million budget, but later gained some success as a cult film.
The film explores themes of friendship, small town, musician, pop star, pop.
The tone is lighthearted.